Javier Sánchez

Core Skill:

Java

Industry Verticals:

Insurance Payments

Programming Languages:

Java Gosu

Visual Basic

Dart

Databases:

Microsoft SQL Server MySQL MongoDB Firebase

Tools & Techniques:

Spring boot

Git Docker

Firebase Functions

Swagger Flutter Maven **Summary:**

A determined and persistent professional, with 20 years of experience who has collaborated in a variety of projects, delivering solutions to small local businesses, contributing and leading teams in the migration process of a multinational metallurgical company, and showcasing his technical skills as a Tech lead at one of the largest insurance companies in Argentina. In the projects he has worked on, he has promoted teamwork, helping his colleagues bring out the best in them, which has naturally led him to leadership positions. These traits, combined with his natural curiosity and tenacity to find solutions, make him a valuable member in any team.

Oualifications:

Educational Background:

System Analyst, Blaise Pascal, San Nicolás, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 2002

Spoken Languages:

Spanish, Native English, B2

Soft Skills:

Analytical Thinking Attention to detail

Autonomy

Critical Thinking

Curiosity Proactivity Leadership Collaboration Self-learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: Payments Tech Lead, in Xelerator project						
						2023-10-27 – 2024-02-16
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:					
Develop a Xelerator Fraud component for the Xelerator ecosystem. The component provides a calculation api, which evaluates a set of rules already configured against a set of data provided, resulting in a numeric score and a fraud / not fraud suggestion. Also providing a CRUD of owners and rules (at global and owner level).	Team tasks (team members: 1 BA/PO, 1 SM, 1 Architect, 1 Tech Lead, 2 Testers, 3 Devs): develop the required component according the Xelerator Standards quality Tasks: • Advise and guide the developers, and mentor the new members • Assist the BAs in technical definitions • Assist the QAs in technical aspects, CATS • Develop the assigned tickets • Design / suggest core technical aspects					
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:				
Java	Spring boot, MongoDB, IntelliJ IDEA, Postman, Jenkins, SonarQube, Scrum, Kubernetes					

Industry sector: Payments

Sr Dev in Xelerator project

2023-03-08 - 2023-10-27

Project descriptions:

Develop a Xelerator SEPA Mandates Manager component for the Xelerator ecosystem. The component provides a solution for managing SEPA mandates, which can be implemented by connecting directly to the application via API or through the application's user interface, which provides a more user friendly approach. Either way, users will be able to create, modify and perform different actions on a mandate as well as search a specific mandate based on specific criteria. For an action to be effective, further approvals by different users might be required. If the action request is rejected, the mandate will remain on the status prior to the change request. SEPA mandate manager allows to limit the accesses to certain functionalities depending of the user, so you can limit a user to create a mandate or approve them but restrict them from modifying them.

Responsibilities:

Job Description / Responsibilities: Team tasks (team members: 2 BA, 1 SM, 1 Architect, 1 Tech Lead, 3 Testers, 4 BE Devs, 2 FE Devs): develop the required component according the Xelerator Standards quality Tasks: • Assist the BAs in technical definitions • Assist the QAs in technical aspects • Develop the assigned tickets • Design data model • Configure and Implement State Machine

Java

Tools & Techniques:

Spring boot, MongoDB, Scrum, Postman, IntelliJ IDEA, Git, Jenkins Testing:

Developer in personal mobile project

2022-09-01 - 2022-11-24						
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:					
Develop a mobile application in Flutter which allows friends and family to predict matches scores of Qatar 2022 Football WorldCup.	Tasks: • Design and develop the frontend in Flutter (login screen, match screen, fixture screen, etc.) • Design the data model and queries to access and save the data in Firestore • Develop Google functions in typescript to process users predictions and calculate their corresponding score according to matches results • Develop a a realtime chat function, that allowed players to communicate within the app, using Firebase Realtime database • Implement login authentication with Firebase (Google, Facebook, email/password) • Distribute new releases with Firebase App Distribution • Deploy web-app version in Firebase Hosting module, allowing non-Android users to access the application					
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:				
Dart, TypeScript	Flutter, Firebase Functions, Firebase Storage					

Industry sector: Insurance

Tech Lead in an insurance company's core system

2022-01-01 - 2022-05-23

Project descriptions:

Implement and customize a Guidewire module, PolicyCenter, a web-based underwriting and policy administration system designed for personal and commercial line carriers in the property and casualty insurance (P&C) industry. PolicyCenter streamlines the process of submitting applications, renewing policies, and managing policy changes for both producers and underwriters.

Programming Languages:

Gosu, SQL

Responsibilities:

Team tasks (team members: 1 Product Owner, 1 Tech Lead, 2 Functional Analyst, 3 Testers, 5 Devs): provide system maintenance, fix bugs and develop new features and integrations for one of its core modules, Guidewire PolicyCenter. Tasks: • Promote GW best practices • Ensure high-quality code using Code reviews • Advise and guide the developers, and mentor the juniors members • Assist the BA in technical definitions • Manage the deployment in all environments, managed with Microsoft Azure • Configure the Git Flow, and branch strategies, also managed with Microsoft Azure and GIT • Issue / troubleshoot tickets to GW and follow up on them • Define the architecture of new processes and ensure data integrity • Participate in estimation process • Work with Agile methodology (Scrum)

Tools	Q.	Techniques:
10013	α	reciniques.

Testing: Jmeter

IntelliJ IDEA, Git, Azure DevOps, Scrum

Industry sector: Insurance

Sr Dev in an insurance company's core system

2016-01-01 - 2019-01-01

Project descriptions:

Implement the rest of the Guidewire's modules, BillingCenter and PolicyCenter, replacing the legacy system. The team received formal training from Guidewire, and participated of the inception process, along with the BAs, where they gained knowledge of the insurance business and defined the gaps that needed to be customized to fit the client's needs. The project spanned a duration of two and a half years and involved a Project Manager (PM) overseeing multiple teams. Teams associated with Guidewire received support from Guidewire consultants. During the lifetime of the project, they worked side by side with the client's BAs, all within scrum framework.

Responsibilities:

Team tasks (22 team members: Team Leader, 5 Testers, 14 Devs, 2 Consultants): development and testing of features already defined in user stories, tracked in Rally, provided by Guidewire consultants. These user stories included mockups and were refined by the BAs. Continuous deployment, code versioning with SVN and bug fixing within the sprint. Tasks: • Participate in meetings with the client's BAs, to define or adjust the specifications for new features • Develop new features • Be in close contact with the Team Leader and the GW consultant, pointing them out possible problems in the code integrations • Solve reported bugs • Modify mockups or suggest changes that better align with the product in the user stories • Participate in estimation process • Help teammates with their assignments • Train users • Work with Agile methodology (Scrum)

Programming Languages:

Gosu, SQL

Tools & Techniques:

Testing:

SVN, Jenkins, IntelliJ IDEA, Rally